So once again welcome to Profit Laddu.  So are
insurance stocks just safe
investments or can they also become multibaggers in the future
?  So, insurance penetration in India
is still very low but is
growing rapidly and hidden in this growth story
are some potential stocks that can
create long term wealth and today we will
talk about six such insurance stocks
and understand where the real
potential lies in them.  So if you
are new to my channel then don't forget to subscribe to the channel
and a small disclaimer
that I am not a SEBI registered analyst
and the video is completely for educational and
learning purposes.  There
is no buy or sell recommendation of any kind from my
side.  So let's start the video.
So the insurance sector is a
structural growth story in India.
As income levels are rising, the
insurance sector is also growing in the same way.
Increasing financial awareness.
Financial awareness is increasing.  So the
insurance sector is also booming.
Awareness is increasing among people.  He is
taking insurance.  There is also a government push
for the insurance sector.
[Music]
So that the common people, the general people, can
easily get insurance.  In this video
we will talk about which are the
strongest insurance stocks.
[Music] Which growth means which are the
growth-capturing stocks and where the
biggest
opportunities can be created for investors.  So
what exactly is happening?  The
insurance sector in India is expanding rapidly
and [nasal sound]
insurance penetration is still around 4%
which is much lower than the developed markets
and the health insurance
demand is increasing a lot post Covid.
Digital distribution channels are being rapidly
adopted and private players are
gaining market share.  So there are six such
insurance companies on which you should
definitely focus.  You should analyze it a little bit and
see.  The first company among them is
Star Health Insurance.  The second
largest company is ICICI lmb General Insurance.   The
third largest company is Neevapa Health Insurance.  The
fourth largest company is SBI Life
Insurance.  The fifth largest company is ICICI
Pencal Life Insurance and the sixth largest company is
Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance.
What exactly is happening?  There are
some strong drivers behind the growth of these sectors, the
first of which is the
rising healthcare cost, that is,
medical inflation is continuously increasing.
People have started looking at insurance as a necessity
and financial
awareness boom has also increased.  Due to which
awareness is increasing in tier to tier three cities.
Digital platforms have made insurance
[music]
accessible and the regulatory push
in which Irda is not Irda but Irdai
which is the insurance regulatory
firms etc., there is
Insurance for All 20247 vision in which
new products and distribution models are being
approved and tax benefits are also being given
on insurance in which the
demand for incentives of section 80C 80D is increasing.
Demographic advantage is also increasing.
Young population equals long-term
policy bearers.
So we will
understand
what are the growth drivers in these 10 stocks and
how these companies can benefit us.
So the first company I mentioned was
Star Health Insurance which is a purely
play health insurance company.  Has a
strong presence in the retail segment.  High
growth but competition [music]
means his competition is also intense.  The second
major player is ICI LBRD General Insurance
which is a diversified general insurance player.
Motor deals in health and corporate segments.  He
is a stable and consistent performer.  The third big company that is
Niva BPA Health Insurance.  Health
Focus is a niche player.  It has an aggressive expansion
strategy and is currently in a growth phase.   The
fourth largest company is SBI Life Insurance
which has strong distribution through SBI
network and high trust factor.
They have consistent growth along with strong margins.  The fifth largest company is
ICICI Potential Life Insurance, which has a
balanced product mix.  UDL
is a production plan and
is slightly sensitive to market cycles.  The sixth largest company is
Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
which has improved profitability.  Their
profitability is improving.  There
is also digital push and cost control.  Gradually a
turnaround story can be created.
Now we have seen all these things that are the
growth factors of these companies.  Now we will
also understand their financials in brief [music].  So come
with me to the computer screen.  Here we
see
what are the financials of Starth & Allied Insurance Company
?  So [music] here's the ROC of 12%.  The
ROE is also 9.37.  If you see here,
one year CAKER is 29% and 3 years is -4%,
that is, it has given good performance in one year
but right now it has
not given that much good performance.  The 3 year old kayaker.
Rest its compound profit growth is -43 and
compound sales growth is also 10%.  If we
look further at
their FII DI holding, the
FII holding is 15% and 20% which is very very
good, 15% 20% is a lot
for a good company and the promoters
holding is also 57% which is very very good,
so here this is also a good
company,
another big company which is leading in this insurance sector is
ICICI
Labord General Insurance Company.  Now let
us look at this.  Look how
amazing its ROE and ROC are.  You can see here
that ROEROC [music] is about
23% and 17%.  Very very good.
Ok?  After that, if we look at this
company, we can also see a little bit about Kager etc.
So if you look at Kiger etc., you will see that nothing special has been given in one year.
Is -4%.  But
their 3 year CAGR is 18%.
Which is very very good.  very good thing.
18% is a lot.  That
means its return for 3 years is around 50%.  If
you go for FD etc. then you
get only 7.5% there.  That too is
not available.  Even its profit growth is
11% and sales growth is 13% which is decent.
After that, if we
look at the FDI holding in it, it is also 22% and
19%.  She also looks fine.   That
means this is also a very good stock.  ICIC
Lambar General Insurance.  The third big
company is Neevapa
Neevapa Health Insurance Company, here the
ROE ROC appears to be a little low, 7-8%.
Now let us see its CAGR etc.,
CAGR etc. also does not appear to be anything special right now, it
appears to be -9, that is okay and
but its sales growth is 24%, it is
going into minus. Let us see its trailing 12 months.
Now is there smart money in it or
not?  Look, the smart money is there
[music] 10% and 16%, okay, that means there's
smart money in the numbers.  That means the
company can do it.  She has not done anything good yet but she
can do something in future.  The fourth largest company
is
SBI Life Insurance,
in which ROE ROCE is 15% and 13%.
You can see that here.
This 15% and 13% is there.
[sound of clearing throat]
What's next?   There is
no significant return in one year.  The
return is 4%.  But the 3 years return is 16%
which is decent.  Can't say it's very good, it's
just good.  After that, if we
look at the FDI holding in this, then
in FDI holding, here we have
19% DII and 21% FII which
looks good.  It is a good thing because 21%
and 19% becomes approximately 40%,
so it is a good thing.  What comes after that is the
next big company which has potential from ICICI.
ICICI
[Music] PDL
ICICI is a Special Asset Management Company.
You can see this.   No no,
we want to see ICICI Life Insurance Company, it is a life
insurance company, so its ROE
ROC is 10% 12%, here we can see,
one year is -14% and 3 years is 7%,
nothing special is visible, but these
companies have
not seen any special rally etc. in the insurance sector yet.  There is no momentum of any kind.  The
entire sector is standing absolutely stagnant.  But
it [music] can.  When the time comes,
all these companies will perform well.
It has FDI holdings of 10% and 11%.
The meaning
is fine.  20% if it is FIDI
then last but not the least is ah Aditya
Bir ah what is this?  Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance
Sun Life
What's in it?
This probably comes under Aditya Birla Capital,
this is Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
and it is priced at Rs 341, it has
137%
FDI holding in it and
after that it has
74%, its one year return in 3 years is
28% [Music] so these are the things of Aditya Birla Capital.
So this is also very good.
ROE ROC 19 is just decent at 11%.
341 Price is going [music].  So till now
we have seen that ah, firstly
what were the growth triggers of the companies, what
can they do, I have discussed all of that with you
and briefly with you the
financials of the companies, whether its
ROE, ROC, CAGR or FII DI
holding, these are the main things.
I am not discussing more
parameters because the video will become very long.
After that we will see what
its market implications are.
You can see it here.
What is in the market implications that we will
look at the short term, the long term
and investor sentiment.
What is clear in the short term is that
insurance stocks
remain relatively stable in market volatility.  And
due to its defensive nature, downside
protection is always available.
What are the long term implications?  The finalizing of
savings trend will continue.
Money will shift into both insurance plus mutual funds
and private insurance
[music] which is where the market leaders can become
companies that are private insurance providers.  And
what is the investor sentiment that long term
investors consider insurance stocks
[music] as compounders but
in the short term the returns may show.
Ok?  After that, what are the
factors that you should look at in the insurance
sector, in the insurance stocks,
so [Music] the biggest
factor in this is what is the premium growth, what is
their new business premium growth
rate, what is the persistence ratio, how many
people are renewing the policy in it, what is the
claim ratio, especially it is a
critical metric for health insurance,
what is the distribution strength,
what is the agent network,
right?  What is embed value?
Key valuation metric for life insurance companies.
What could be the risks?   There
is high competition, regulatory changes,
claim ratio may spike.
What are opportunities?  It is an under-penetrated
market.  The rising middle class is
driving the digital insurance boom.
What is the key takeaway?  The insurance sector is a
long term structural growth story in India.
Health insurance
is the fastest growing segment
and players like SBI and ICICI LBR
provide stability.  Star Health [music]
and Neevapa which is a high growth but higher risk
play.  Insurance Stocks Slow
Insurance stocks can be slow but
powerful compounders.  That means the
insurance stocks will gradually
give you returns.  It
can give good returns in the long term, but it
may provide you very slow returns.
What is the overall conclusion?  The overall
conclusion is that the insurance sector
seems quite boring.  Isn't it?  But
wealth creation often happens in boring sectors.
You should remember this.  And
if India's insurance penetration
increases, if these companies
create massive value in 10-15 years, then the
question is whether you will chase short term gains
or take advantage of long term compounding.
And if you
want similar deep analysis then do subscribe to my channel
and a small
disclaimer is that I am not a SEBI registered
analyst and the video is completely for
educational and learning purpose [music].  There
is no buy or sell recommendation of any kind and please let me know in the comments
which of these stocks is
your favorite stock
in the insurance sector [music].  So I will
wait for that and that was all from my side for today
in this video.  So thank you.
Thank you so much.